# Seungone Kim

☑ louisdebroglie@kaist.ac.kr • ♦ https://github.com/SeungoneKim

My main research goal is to build neural models with enhanced reasoning capabilities and to supplement insufficient knowledge. Specifically, I am interested in injecting and utilizing commonsense knowledge to/with neural models [C2], analyzing to which extent neural models can do commonsense reasoning [P1], and enabling neural models to follow the given instructions [C3, P2].

#### Education

Yonsei University

Seoul, Korea

B.S. in Computer Science

March 2018 - February 2023

Advisor: Jinyoung Yeo

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Seoul, Korea March 2023 –

M.S. in Artificial Intelligence

Advisor: Minjoon Seo

#### **Publications**

Peer-Reviewed Conference Papers.

- [C1] SG-MLP: Switch Gated Multi-Layer Perceptron Model for Natural Language Understanding
   Annual Conference of Korea Information Processing Society, 2021 (ACK 2021)
   Guijin Son, Seungone Kim, Se June Joo, Woojin Cho, JeongEun Nah
   [Paper] [Code]
- [C2] Mind the Gap! Injecting Commonsense Knowledge for Abstractive Dialogue Summarization
   Proceedings of the 29th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING 2022)
   Seungone Kim\*, Se June Joo\*, Hyungjoo Chae\*, Chaehyeong Kim\*, Seungwon Hwang, Jinyoung Yeo [Paper] [Code]
- [C3] CoTEVer: Chain of Thought Prompting Annotation Toolkit for Explanation Verification
   The 17th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics Demo Track (EACL 2023 Demo)

**Seungone Kim**, Se June Joo, Yul Jang, Hyungjoo Chae, Jinyoung Yeo [Code]

# Preprints....

[P1] Can Language Models perform Abductive Commonsense Reasoning?

# Seungone Kim

[Paper] [Code]

• [P2] Exploring the Benefits of Training Expert Language Models over Instruction Tuning Under Review

Joel Jang, **Seungone Kim**, Seonghyeon Ye, Doyoung Kim, Lajanugen Logeswaran, Moontae Lee, Kyungjae Lee, Minjoon Seo [Paper] [Code]

# Research Experience

Yonsei University Seoul, Korea

Internship at Soft Computing Laboratory

Apr 2021 - Aug 2021

I have participated in 'Industry - University Assignments' between Yonsei University and Samsung Electronics Research. I have built a neural model that transforms documents into tabular data. I built the overall pipeline along with a demo system to test it out.

**Seoul National University** 

Seoul, Korea

Research Internship at Language and Data Intelligence Laboratory

Sep 2021 - Jun 2022

I have participated in a research project building a multilingual language model for low-resource languages via continual cross-lingual transfer during pre-training. Also, I have participated in the initial stage of building a Korean Language Model where I pre-trained a 11B sized decoder-only model with korean text corpus from scratch.

Yonsei University Seoul, Korea

Undergraduate Thesis advised by Conversational Intelligence Laboratory

Sep 2021 – Present
I have published my undergraduate thesis at COLING 2022 (long) as a first author [C2]. I proposed a method

that injects commonsense knowledge inferences to solve abstractive dialogue summarization.

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Seoul, Korea

Research Internship at Language and Knowledge Laboratory

Jul 2022 - Jan 2023

I participated in a research project building a distributed expert language model that tackles the weakness of Instruction-tuned LMs such as T0 and FLAN [P2].

#### **Technical and Personal skills**

- Programming Languages: Python(Proficient), C++, C, Java
- Frameworks / Software Skills: PyTorch(Proficient), PyTorch Lightning(Proficient), Transformers(Proficient), FairSeq, Torch Geometric, NLTK, SpaCy
- O Software Skills: Linux, Google Cloud Platform, Docker, LATEX, Git, Wandb

## **Invited Talks**

Commonsense Knowledge Consortium 1st Workshop

Hosted by II Chul Moon(KAIST), Chanyoung Park(KAIST), Jinyoung Yeo(Yonsei), Seungwon Hwang(SNU), Joseph Lim(KAIST), Jonghyeon Choi (Yonsei)

Presented about 'The Challenges in Commonsense Reasoning'

Yonsei University AI Workshop

Hosted by Jonghyeon Choi (Yonsei)

Presented my paper accepted at COLING 2022[C2]

### **Services**

O Conference Reviewer: EACL 2023, ACL 2023

# **Honors and Awards**

#### **Certificate of Achievement**

**US** Department of the Army

Awarded as Sergeant

August 2020

I have served as a KATUSA (Korean Army Augmented to United States Army) in January 2019 - August 2020. I worked at a office consisted of Chief Warrant Officers who would fly helicopters to move Generals across the peninsula.

Excellence Award at Annual Conference of KIPS, 2021 Korea Information Processing Society

Marked as Top 8 papers

Awarded with my paper at ACK 2021[C1].

**Grand Prize in Graduation Capstone** 

Yonsei University

Marked as Top 3 projects

July 2022

Awarded with my paper at COLING 2022[C2].

Yonsei Al Workshop NLP Best Paper Award Samsung Electronics Research, Yonsei University
October 2022

Awarded with my paper at COLING 2022[C2].

Semester Academic Excellence Scholarship

Yonsei University

Fall 2020, Spring 2021, Fall 2021, Spring 2022, Fall 2022

High / Highest Academic Honors

Yonsei University

Fall 2020, Spring 2021, Spring 2022